Hello, and welcome back. I want to give you an example of a very
【未完成版本】 大家好 欢迎回来 我想给大家讲解一个例子
particular and important application of partial differential equations and
是图像处理中 关于偏微分方程和
variation of formulations in image processing.
变分方程的非常特殊而重要的应用
And this will put together, some of the concepts that we have just learned, in a
我们会将一些已经学过的概念 以简单的方式组合在一起
very, very simple fashion. So, what we are going to do is we're
所以 我们马上要进行
going to do histogram modification with partial differential equations.
基于偏微分方程的直方图修正
We know how to do histogram modification. We have learned that a few weeks ago.
我们知道如何进行直方图修正 这在几周前已经学过了
Now I'm going to show you how to do that with partial differential equations.
现在 我会讲解如何利用偏微分方程进行直方图修改
The basic idea is, as we always do with partial differential equations.
其基本思想 正如我们在偏微分方程中接触的
We want to deform the image towards a certain goal.
我们想把图像转换为特定的目标
In particular now, we want to change the contrast.
特别地 现在我们想要改变对比度
We want to deform the image in such a way that improves the contrast, and we can
我们想改善对比度从而改变图像
start thinking about how to do that if we understand partial differential
于是我们可以开始思考 如何利用偏微分方程达到这一目的
equations. We want to stretch the grey values of the
我们希望延展图像的灰度值
image. Now, how we are going to do that?
那么 现在要怎么做呢？
In this particular case, we're going back into histogram modification.
这时候 让我们回顾一下直方图修正
We know how to do that. We learned that.
我们已经学过 如何做直方图修正
It's just a simple map that we learned a few weeks ago.
正如几周前所学的 只是简单的映射
So here is how you do it with a partial differential equation, as an
这里是一个例子 说明如何利用偏微分方程
illustration. Here is the partial differential
这就是偏微分方程
equation. You're going to deform the image,
我们将要根据给定像素本身的值
according to its own pixel value at the given pixel, minus the number of pixels
减去周围大于自身像素值的像素的数量 进行图像变形
that are great than u. So, you have an image,
所以 我们有一幅图像
you're sitting at a certain pixel, and say How am I going to change these
选中某一点像素 判断应该如何改变这一像素值
pixels? Very simple. You look at your own value, you look at
非常简单 我们考虑自身的像素值
how many values are above you, and you deform yourself according to that, to the
然后看看周围有多少像素值是大于自身像素值的
difference between both of them. Now why is this doing the histogram
再根据两者的差改变自身像素值 为什么这是在做直方图修正呢？
modification? Very simple. Remember what we talked.
道理也很简单 还记得我们说过
Normally you deform the image equal to your goal. Now, when you get to steady
通常来说我们会将图像变形为目标图像 现在当你进入稳定状态
state, these becomes 0. So the image becomes equal the pixel value at, of the
这个值就变成0了 所以图像的像素值就等于
image, becomes equal to the number of pixel values, above your own value.
大于自身像素值的像素的个数
And this is exactly, if you go back to your notes on histogram modification,
而这就是 如果你回忆一下直方图修正的笔记
this is exactly histogram equalization. So this is a very interesting way to
会发现这其实就是直方图均衡化 这是实现直方图均衡化的
achieve histogram equalization. Instead of doing a look-up table, as we
非常有趣的方法 不需要如前面所学的那样 列出一张表格
learned, we just slowly deform the image towards it.
我们只需要慢慢进行图像变形 来达到目的
Now, you may ask yourself, why do I have to implement a partial differential
现在可能你想问 为什么我一定要使用偏微分方程
equation that is computationally more expensive than just doing that look-up
这一个计算量远大于列表格的方法？
table? There's a couple of reasons. One, pedagogically, I'm giving you these
这里有几个原因 其一 基于教育因素
as an example of a partial differential equation acheiving something that, we
我想给你们一个应用偏微分方程的例子
want to achieve like, exactly the condition for histogram equalization.
来实现 比如 直方图均衡化
Now, there is another reason. You might stop, this deformation, at any
另一个原因是 我们可以随时停止图像变形
moment. In histogram equalization, you do the
在直方图均衡化中 我们需要计算
math. There is no intermediate solution.
并不会直接得出结果
If that was too much contrast, then you're in trouble.
如果对比度太大 我们就会很困扰
There is no way, either, no way back either.
而又没有办法 复原到原始图像
The original image, or that. Here you can start stretching your
或者得到理想图像 在这里我们可以一点点拉伸直方图
histogram. Start moving towards histogram
慢慢朝直方图均衡化的目标变形
equalization. But you can stop before you finish that,
但是如果我们已经满意现在的成果
if you are already satisfied with the result.
或者现在的成果比继续完成直方图均衡化的结果还要好
Or even if that result is better than going all the way to histogram
那么我们也可以在得到最终结果前停下来
equalization. So those are examples of why you might
【未完成版本】 这些例子说明了
want to do a partial differential equation instead of a lookup table.
为什么我们愿意使用偏微分方程而不是表格的原因
Now, of course. In the same way that you can do partial ?
当然 与使用偏微分方程一样
equations you can try to do this contrast enhancement by solving a variational
我们也可以尝试求解变分问题 来进行对比度增强
problem. And here is an example of such a
这里就是一个变分问题的例子
variational problem. Again the art here is for you to start
同理 这里的技巧是
putting terms in the variational problem that will help you to achieve your goal.
逐渐在变分问题中增加项 帮助我们实现目标
So here is one term. Remember, what we try is to optimize for this, it's
这里就是一个项 记得 我们尝试最优化这个项
basically to minimize or to maximize, in this case, to minimize this energy.
或者是最小化或者是最大化 而这里是需要求最小值
So this is a term that normally you put it in this kind of things, and here I'm
所以这个就是我们增加的项
assuming the image is between 0 and 1. It has been normalized, so the pixel
我们假设图像像素值在0到1之间 需要先做归一化
values are between 0 and 1. You say, you know, I want the image to be
以便像素值规范在0和1之间 我们现在想改善这幅图像
nice. I don't want it just to be too far away
我们不希望像素值 太过偏离平均灰度值
from the average grey values, and that you achieve by this.
于是用这一项达到我们的要求
On the other hand, you want contrast. So here is the contrast.
另一方面 我们也需要改善对比度 所以这里是对比度
You don't want the pixel values all to be together.
我们不希望像素值都是一样的
If I don't have this term If I remove this term, the solution of this is a
如果我们没有这一项 或者去掉这一项
constant value equal to half. All the pixels values are in the middle
结果会是这个常量的一半 所有的像素值都聚集在中间
all together. That's not what I wanted.
这并不是我们想要的
I want them to be nicely distributed, as expressed here, but I also wanted
我们想要像素值很好地分布 正如这里所表示的
contrast. And note that we have a minus sign here,
我们也需要对比度 注意这里有一个减号
and, because I want to encourage Fix the values to get far away.
而且 因为我希望像素值分散开来
Now, I don't want them to go crazy far away, and that's why you add other types
但是我们又不想它们分散得太远 这就是为什么需要添加其他的项
of terms. Now, we have integrals here, which is,
现在 我们有积分
where do I count these? Do I count it all around the image? Now, this is also part
我要在什么范围计算积分呢？ 我需要对整幅图像进行计算吗？
of your gain? You can say, hey, I'm going to just ask for these contrasts in
现在 这也是你的策略 你可以要求
certain regions of the image. So, you can do the integral only for
只在图像的某些区域改善对比度 所以只需要对这些区域做积分
Or you can say, I'm going to ask for this
或者你可以说
contrast only for certain. Ranges of pixel values.
我只要对特定范围的像素值改善对比度
So you can actually become very creative in, designing, this variation of
我们可以极具创意性地设计这一个变分式子
formulation, this same for this direct pd's.
直接使用偏微分方程也是一样的
Something that you couldn't do when you had to look up table.
实现一些 在查询表格中不能做到的事
It was like 1 to 1, from here to here, There's nothing in between.
表格法就像是一对一 从这里到那里 没有中间结果
Here, it gives you a lot of flexibility to become very, very creative.
而这里给我们许多灵活性 从而变得更具创意
So let's see some results of this. Here we have two examples.
让我们来看看一些成果 这里有两个例子
Contrast enhancement here. Now the interesting thing here, you might
这个是对比度增强 有趣的是
notice that basically, this is kind of localized.
你们可能注意到了 这是局部性的
Every region, kind of move by itself, and there no mixing of the region, and these
每一个区域 都是根据本身进行变换 区域间没有混杂
were achieved by playing with those eastern bound, boundaries, with those
这是通过 抱歉 是通过集成边界实现的
integration boundaries, sorry. And making sure that things that have
并且确保相似的像素值
similar pixel values, or in this case is exactly the same piece of values, kind of
或者 这里的相同的像素值
moves together. So, here's an example of an artificial
都能聚集到一起  所以这是一个仿真图像的例子
image to illustrate how these variational formulations can give you contrasting
用来说明 变分方程如何帮助我们增强对比度
enhansements that preserve the shapes of the image.
而又保持了图像的形状
And here is another example of a natural image.
这里是另一个自然图像的例子
I hope you can appreciate that through the video, that this is a very dark
我希望你可以通过视频欣赏到 这是非常暗的图像
image, and here you have much vivid colors, a much nicer looking image.
而这里得到了一张更加鲜艳 更加漂亮的图像
And this 2 examples are acheived with these PDEs, or variations and
这两个例子都利用PDEs 或者变分方程来实现增强
formulations. Those are two different, and one gives
这里的两个不同的例子
you some capabilities, the other gives you another capabilities, and playing
一个实现了某种性能 另一个实现另一种性能
with the integral limits and playing with the terms inside the integrals, you can
而通过调整积分范围和积分项
start achieving the kind of application that you want for this type of contrast
我们可以实现这一类对比度增强的应用
enhancement. So I hope you enjoyed this example.
希望大家喜欢这个例子
It illustrates both the concept of PD's, that we can almost achieve any condition
它说明了PDEs的概念 当PDEs到达稳定状态后
that we want if we run the PD to steady state, and also it illustrates how we can
几乎可以实现我们想要的任意效果 同时也说明了
design variational formulation For an extremely important application that is
如何为极其重要的对比度增强应用 设计变分方程
Contrast Enhancement. Thank you very much.
感谢大家
Looking forward to seeing you in the future videos.
【未完成版本】 期待在之后的视频中再见